Audiovisual Collection Relating to Georgia O'Keeffe and the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum, 1938-2015, undated MS.44
Georgia O'Keeffe Museum
Audiovisual Collection Relating to Georgia O'Keeffe and the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum
1938 - 2015, undated
Georgia O'Keeffe Museum
MS.44
24
4.92 Linear Feet
Contains recordings of productions and events that are either related to Georgia O'Keeffe and her contemporaries or the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum dating from 1938 to 2015. Types of productions and events include broadcasts, home recordings, interviews, lectures, and symposia on audio cassettes, microcassettes, VHS tapes, and DVDs.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of archival audiovisual recordings requires advance notice to ensure playback equipment is available.
Existence and Location of Copies
Some of the video and sound recordings in this collection have been copied for research access and digital copies are available onsite.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into two series, video recordings and sound recordings. Within the two series the materials are arranged by type of recording and then chronologically.
Acquisition Information
This is an artificial collection created by the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum. The materials were collected from a variety of sources from 1997 to 2015.
This collection is the physical property of the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum. The Museum holds literary rights only for material created by Museum personnel or given to the Museum with such rights specifically assigned. The collection is subject to all copyright laws. The researcher assumes full responsibility for observing all copyright, property, and libel laws as they apply. Contact the Archivist for further copyright and publication information as it pertains to this collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains recordings of productions and events that are either related to Georgia O'Keeffe and her contemporaries or the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum. Types of productions and events include broadcasts, home recordings, interviews, lectures, and symposia.
Types of recording media found in the collection include: audio cassettes, microcassettes, VHS tapes, and DVDs. Some materials have been digitized and reformatted over time.
This artificial collection contains materials that were collected by the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum over a period of time and from a variety of sources.
Video recordings; Interviews; Artists -- Interviews; Sound recordings; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Georgia O'Keeffe Museum
- Video Recordings, 1938 - 2015, undated; Series 1
  - Broadcasts, 1981 - 2015, undated; 1.1
    - CBS Sunday Morning: Georgia O'Keeffe, 1981-08-30, 1987-11-01; 1 moving images DVD; Compilation of two broadcasts. Bruce Morton hosts 1981 segment, Charles Kuralt hosts 1987 segment. Includes interviews with O'Keeffe and Juan Hamilton. (Box 1, Item 1)
    - CBS Sunday Morning: Georgia O'Keeffe, c. 1986; 1 moving images Duration 00:12:00 VHS; Black and white version of Charles Kuralt presenting Bruce Morton segment from 5 years ago (1981). See related DVDV for final broadcast version. This is only an introduction by Kuralt. (Box 1, Item 2)
    - CBS Sunday Morning: Interview with Juan Hamilton about Georgia O'Keeffe, 1987-11-01; 1 moving images Duration: 00:12:00 VHS; Black and white, unnarrated version of November 1, 1987 broadcast. Charles Kuralt interviews Juan Hamilton. See DVD for final broadcast version. (Box 1, Item 3)
    - ABC Good Morning America: Interview with Juan Hamilton at Abiquiu, 1992-11-20; 1 moving images VHS (Box 1, Item 4)
    - BBC The Late Show: Georgia O'Keeffe, 1993-04-19; 5 moving images Duration 00:40:00 VHS; Matthew Collings host and narrator: Maria Chabot, Roxana Robinson, Anna Chave, Sarah Greenough, O'Keeffe clips throughout, Louise Bourgeois, Sarah Whitaker Peters, Barbara Lynes, Katherine Krueger, Juan Hamilton. (Box 1, Item 5-9)
    - KOB TV Cavalcade of Entertainment, Reflections on Canvas: Georgia O'Keeffe, 1996-02-12; 1 moving images Duration 00:28:00 VHS; Carla Aragon host: James Moore, Director of Albuquerque Museum, David Turner, Director of Museum of Fine Arts, Ellen Bradbury, Recursos de Santa Fe. (Box 1, Item 10)
    - KRQE TV Georgia O'Keeffe stamp first day of issue news coverage, 1996-05-23; 1 moving images VHS (Box 1, Item 11)
    - BBC American Visions series: The Republic of Virtue, Early American Art, 1996-11-03; 1 moving images Duration 00:50:00 VHS (Box 1, Item 12)
    - BBC American Visions: Robert Hughes interviews Maria Chabot, 1996-12-08; 2 moving images Duration 01:30:00 VHS; Robert Hughes interviews Maria Chabot for the American Vision series, episode 5 of 8, The Wave from the Atlantic. Unedited. Includes footage of Abiquiu/Ghost Ranch. (Box 1, Item 13-14)
    - BBC American Visions series: The Wave from the Atlantic, 1996-12-08; 1 moving images Duration 00:59:00 VHS (Box 2, Item 1)
    - KOAT TV Time Magazine Selects New Mexico as Coolest State, 1997-05-19; 1 moving images Duration 00:02:00 VHS; Includes footage of O'Keeffe art. Handwritten notes in case. (Box 2, Item 2)
    - KRQE TV Tourism Santa Fe: Georgia O'Keeffe Museum, 1997-05-27; 1 moving images Duration 00:05:00 VHS; Includes footage of Georgia O'Keeffe Museum under construction. Handwritten notes in case. (Box 2, Item 3)
    - KOAT TV Abiquiu home tour, 1997-07-16; 1 moving images Duration 00:02:33 VHS; Terry Cernuto reporter, John Blake photojournalist, unedited. (Box 2, Item 4)
    - KOAT TV, KRQE TV Georgia O'Keeffe Museum opening, 1997-07-16-1997-07-17; 1 moving images Duration 00:24:00 VHS; Footage from KOAT: Abiquiu tour. Includes footage of O'Keeffe from WNET, ABC (Good Morning America 7/17, audio of O'Keeffe, Juan Hamilton interview), NBC (Today Show, Katie Couric), CBS Sunday Morning. Notes in case. (Box 2, Item 5)
    - KOAT ABC NBC CBS Georgia O'Keeffe Museum opening news coverage, 1997-07-17; 1 moving images VHS (Box 2, Item 6)
    - SFCTV6 Georgia O'Keeffe Museum opening, 1997-07-17; 3 moving images Duration 00:30:00 VHS; Complete footage of opening ceremonies and ribbon cutting. Handwritten notes in case. (Box 2, Item 7-9)
    - Georgia O'Keeffe Museum opening news coverage, 1997-07-17-1997-08-27; 1 moving images VHS; ABC CBS KLUZ PBS NBC. Notes in case. (Box 2, Item 10)
    - CBS Sunday Morning: Tease and Her Land & Landscape, Georgia O'Keeffe Museum Opening, 1997-07-27; 1 moving images Duration 00:09:00 VHS; Final broadcast version. (Box 2, Item 11)
    - CBS Sunday Morning: Tease and Her Land & Landscape, Georgia O'Keeffe Museum Opening, 1997-07-27; 1 moving images Duration 00:09:00 VHS; Unedited version. Incomplete audio. Handwritten note in case. (Box 2, Item 12)
    - PBS Lehrer Report: Georgia O'Keeffe Museum opening, 1997-08-27; 1 moving images Duration 00:12:00 VHS; Handwritten notes in case. (Box 2, Item 13)
    - NBC Today Show: Georgia O'Keeffe Museum opening, 1997; 2 moving images Duration 00:05:00 VHS; Katie Couric presents. Handwritten notes in case. (Box 3, Item 1-2)
    - WETA TV Around Town: O'Keeffe on Paper at National Gallery of Art, 2000-04-13; 1 moving images Duration 00:05:00 VHS; Handwritten notes in case. (Box 3, Item 3)
    - ABCTV Travel Salad: Texas and New Mexico Special, 2004-04-03-2004-04-24; 1 moving images VHS; Non-English- Japanese? At minute 1:06 Georgia O'Keeffe Museum walk-through. (Box 3, Item 4)
    - Georgia O'Keeffe Museum, Sachiko Sugiyama, 2004; 3 moving images Duration 00:45:00 VHS (Box 3, Item 5-7)
    - CBS Sunday Morning Almanac: Georgia O'Keeffe, 2015-11-15; 2 moving images DVD (Box 7, Item 16-17)
    - TV Tokyo-nexus Great Masters of Art: Georgia O'Keeffe, undated; 3 moving images VHS (Box 3, Item 8-10)
  - Events, 1988; 1.2
    - Portrait of an Artist: Georgia O'Keeffe, 1988; 1 moving images VHS; J. Parker Copley dance company performs a tribute to Georgia O'Keeffe at the Power Center for the Performing Arts, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan. (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Home Recordings, 1938-1996; 1.3
    - Georgia O'Keeffe receiving honorary degree from College of William and Mary, 1938; 1 moving images Duration 00:02:52 VHS; Home movie documents parts of the 1938 honorary degree ceremony when Georgia O'Keeffe received an honorary Doctor of Fine Arts degree from College of William and Mary. No sound. Digital file available. (Box 4, Item 2)
      Degrees; home movies
    - James Lebron home recording of Georgia O'Keeffe in New Mexico, 1965 or 1966; 1 moving images VHS; Home movie of Georgia O'Keeffe at Ghost Ranch. (Box 4, Item 3)
    - James Lebron home recording of Georgia O'Keeffe in New Mexico, 1965 or 1966; 1 moving images Duration 00:13:35 DVD; Home movie of O'Keeffe at Ghost Ranch. (Box 7, Item 6)
    - Allene LaPides Gallery, 1996-08; 1 moving images VHS; Handheld footage of walkthrough, interior/exterior, poor lighting/audio. (Box 4, Item 4)
  - Interviews, 1993, 1997, undated; 1.4; Arranged alphabetically by interviewee last name.
    - Interview with Dan Budnik, undated; 2 moving images Duration 00:27:00 VHS; Includes short video of O'Keeffe and Juan Hamilton taken by Budnik. (Box 4, Item 5-6)
    - Interview with Letitia (Tish) Evans Frank, 1993-08-13; 1 moving images VHS; Uncut version of interview with Letitia (Tish) Evans Frank (1926-2009) about her friendship with Georgia O'Keeffe. By Tom McCarthy and Katie Peters. (Box 4, Item 7)
    - Interview with Juan Hamilton in Abiquiu, undated; 1 moving images Duration 00:47:00 VHS; Unedited. Female interviewer and, Asian production team. (Box 4, Item 8)
    - Interview with Richard Littlefield, undated; 1 moving images Duration 00:17:00 VHS; Stories told about Martin Weber party, Venice, Peggy Guggenheim, mid-70s, Claire Falkenstein designed jewelry for and presented to O'Keeffe. (Box 4, Item 9)
    - Interview with Todd Webb, 1997-07-22; 1 moving images Duration 02:00:00 VHS; Interview with Todd and Lucille Webb about career and relationship with Stieglitz and O'Keeffe. Unedited. Notes in case. Original on beta at the Palace of the Governors, Santa Fe, NM. (Box 4, Item 10)
  - Production, c. 1948 - 2012, undated; 1.5
    - Land of Enchantment: Southwest U.S.A., c. 1948; 1 moving images DVD; Credits: Dir/Writ. Henwar Rodakiewicz, Photog. Boris Kaufman, Ed. Rosemarie Hickson; Mus. Manuel Rosenthal; Narr. Philip Bourneuf. Contributor: Producer, U.S. Information Service. Made by Affiliated Film Productions. Features section on Georgia O'Keeffe at Ghost Ranch. (Box 7, Item 1)
    - The Alfred Stieglitz Collection, 1987; 1 moving images Duration 00:10:00 VHS; Carl Van Vechten Gallery. (Box 5, Item 1)
    - Sol Y Sombra, 1996; 1 moving images Duration 00:35:00 VHS; Promotional video. (Box 5, Item 2)
    - Sol Y Sombra 3rd edition, c. 1996; 1 moving images Duration 00:15:00 VHS; Promotional video. (Box 5, Item 3)
    - Desert Beauty, The Painter Georgia O'Keeffe, 2012; 4 moving images DVD; Wuste-Schonheit. Die Malerin Georgia O'Keeffe. German film. (Box 7, Item 15)
    - Maria Chabot: Los Luceros, undated; 2 moving images Duration 00:13:00 VHS; Handwritten notes in case. (Box 5, Item 4-5)
- Sound Recordings, 1960 - 2008, undated; Series 2
  - Events, 1989-2002; 2.1
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art O'Keeffe Dinner, circa 1989-06-06; 1 sound recording Duration 00:38:19. audiocassette (Box 6, Item 1)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: James Kraft Barbara Buhler Lynes, 1990-10-5-1990-10-7; 2 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:44:36, Side B 00:46:09. 2 audiocassettes. Tape 2 is copy. (Box 6, Item 2-3)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: Barbara Buhler Lynes Lisa Messinger, 1990-10-05-1990-10-07; 2 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:46:23, Side B 00:29:52. 2 audiocassettes. Tape 2 is copy. (Box 6, Item 4-5)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: Anna Chave, 1990-10-05-1990-10-07; 3 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:45:53, Side B 00:26:27. 3 audiocassettes. Tapes 2 and 3 are copies. (Box 6, Item 6-8)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: Rob Silverman Sharyn Udall, 1990-10-5-1990-10-7; 2 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:45:24, Side B 00:45:31. 2 audiocassettes. Tape 2 is copy. (Box 6, Item 9-10)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: Sharyn Udall Hunter Drohojowska, 1990-10-05-1990-10-07; 3 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:43:04, Side B 00:32:06. 3 audiocassettes. Tapes 2 and 3 are copies. (Box 6, Item 11-13)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: Meridel Rubenstein Roxanna Robinson, 1990-10-05-1990-10-07; 3 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:46:15, Side B 00:46:17. 3 audiocassettes. Tapes 2 and 3 are copies. (Box 6, Item 14-16)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: Laurie Lisle Sue Davidson Lowe, 1990-10-05-1990-10-07; 3 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:46:41, Side B 00:46:23. 3 audiocassettes. Tapes 2 and 3 are copies. (Box 6, Item 17-19)
    - O'Keeffe Conference: Sue Davidson Lowe, 1990-10-05-1990-10-07; 3 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: 00:38:50 3 audiocassettes. Tapes 2 and 3 are copies. (Box 6, Item 20-22)
    - Hillary Clinton and Ray Krueger, Bear Lake unveiling at White House, 1997-10; 1 sound recording Duration Side A 00:13:29, Side B 00:11:35. audiocassette (Box 6, Item 23)
    - Creativity and Madness Conference, 2002-08-01; 1 sound recording Duration 00:44:23 audiocassette; Discussion of O'Keeffe. (Box 6, Item 24)
  - Interviews, 1960 - 2004, undated; 2.2
    - Interview with Georgia O'Keeffe by Charlotte Willard, 1960; 6 moving images DVD; 3 Wave file format. 3 CDA file format. (Box 7, Item 2-5)
    - Interview with Georgia O'Keeffe by Agapita (Judy) Lopez, 1976; 6 moving images DVD; 3 Wave format. 3 CDA format. (Box 7, Item 7-10)
    - Interview with Georgia O'Keeffe by Laura Soulliere of the National Park Service, 1981-03-25; 2 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: Side A 00:44:32, Side B 25:31. 2 audiocassettes. Audiocassette 2 is copy.; Conducted in the sitting room at Abiquiu, New Mexico. (Box 6, Item 25-26)
    - Interview with Beaumont Newhall on Georgia O'Keeffe, 1982-06-23; 1 sound recording Duration 00:32:19 audiocassette (Box 6, Item 27)
    - Interview with Fritz Scholder on Georgia O'Keeffe, 1982-08-03; 1 sound recording Duration Side A 00:33:54, Side B 00:29:14 audiocassette; Notes in case. (Box 6, Item 28)
    - Juan Hamilton, 1982-08-05; 1 sound recording Duration Side A 00:35:27, Side B 00:21:05 audiocassette (Box 6, Item 29)
    - Meridel Rubenstein, 1982-08-06; 2 sound recording Duration audiocassette 1: 00:12:00. Duration audiocassette 2: Side A 00:35:26, Side B 00:34:31. audiocassettes (Box 6, Item 30-31)
    - Interview with Ruby Cole Archer by Al Kochka, 1986-04-14; 1 sound recording Duration Side A 00:14:47, Side B 00:29:21. audiocassette; Interviewed by Al Kochka, Director of the Amarillo Art Center. Ruby Cole Archer was a student of O'Keeffe's at West Texas State Normal College, Canyon, Texas. (Box 6, Item 32)
    - WNVR Interview with Barbara Buhler Lynes, 2004-02-02; 1 sound recording Duration Side A 00:47:00, Side B 00:46:59. audiocassette; News program and interview with Barbara Buhler Lynes. (Box 6, Item 33)
    - KUNM Interview with Maria Chabot, Barbara Buhler Lynes and Leslie Clark, 2004-02; 1 sound recording Duration Side B 00:25:40 (Side A is blank). audiocassette (Box 6, Item 34)
    - Interview with Belarmino Lopez by Barbara Buhler Lynes, undated; 1 sound recording Duration 00:39:18. audiocassette (Box 6, Item 35)
    - Interview with Maria Chabot, undated; 1 sound recording Duration Side A 00:31:20, Side B 00:10:09. microcassette (Box 6, Item 36)
  - Production, 1985 - 2008, undated; 2.3
    - Georgia O'Keeffe Remembered, by Al Kochka, Director of the Amarillo Art Center, 1985; 1 sound recording audiocassette (Box 6, Item 37)
    - Coors American Taste Santa Fe Report: Georgia O'Keeffe, 1990-11-17; 1 sound recording audiocassette (Box 6, Item 38)
    - Oliver Taplin discussion of O'Keeffe show at Hayward Gallery, 1993-08-04-1993-09-04; 1 sound recording audiocassette (Box 6, Item 39)
    - Two Lives: A Conversation in Paintings and Photographs O'Keeffe and Stieglitz, 1993; 1 sound recording audiocassette (Box 6, Item 40)
    - The Georgia O'Keeffe I Knew Volume 1 by Tio Manzanarez, 1997; 1 sound recording audiocassette; Employed by O'Keeffe as her driver, additional notes on case. Audiocassette cover signed by Tio Manzanerez. (Box 6, Item 41)
    - The Georgia O'Keeffe I Knew Volume 1 by Tio Manzanarez, 1997; 3 moving images DVD; Wave file format. (Box 7, Item 11-12)
    - KGNU Boulder: O'Keeffe Days In A Life, 2002-09-04; 1 moving images Duration 00:55:45 DVD; Featuring poet Carol S. Merrill with host Sandy Karng. (Box 7, Item 13)
    - Smithsonian American Art Museum: Natural Affinities Georgia O'Keeffe and Ansel Adams, exhibition podcast, c. 2008; 1 moving images DVD (Box 7, Item 14)
    - National Gallery of Art: Georgia O'Keeffe (acoustiguide), undated; 1 sound recording audiocassette (Box 6, Item 42)